ROSEANNA FERGUSON

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a fourth year MMath student at the University of Warwick. Logical reasoning, basic Java and Matlab are some of the skills I gained as part of my studies. In addition, the research I am undertaking this summer shows a clear aptitude for understanding and solving complex problems.

My ability to use enthusiasm and creativity to succeed in a variety of organisations and roles demonstrates versatility. Public speaking and liaising duties in societies shows proven capabilities in communication. The strong interpersonal skills I possess can be demonstrated through volunteering roles such as teaching in South Africa. Finally, I am passionate about contributing to any community I belong to, displayed by my activities in Athena Swan.

EDUCATION

Warwick University, UK

Oct 2012 - Jun 2016

MMath in Mathematics

First Year: 76%, Second Year: 68%, Third Year: 87%

Relevant modules: Programming for Scientists (Java), Maths by Computer (Matlab), Linear Algebra, Abstract Algebra, Combinatorics, Combinatorial Optimisation, Logic, Introduction to Topology

Harrogate Grammar School, Harrogate, UK

Sept 2004 - Jun 2012

A-Levels: Mathematics(\mathbf{A}^*), Further Mathematics(\mathbf{A}^*), Physics(\mathbf{A}^*), Chemistry(\mathbf{A}^*), Economics(\mathbf{A})

AS-Levels: Additional Further Mathematics

GCSEs: 4 A*s and 2 As

WORK EXPERIENCE

Warwick University, UK - Undergraduate Researcher

Jun 2015 - Sept 2015

- · Prepared by taking an advanced module not for credit. Contributed to publishable work in this area.
- · Conducted research on the optimal timing decision for executives of when to exercise options given they can exert managerial effort to influence the underlying stock price.
- · Analysed and discerned unfamiliar material which developed competency in reading academic papers.
- · Summarised findings into a poster and presented to academics. Enhanced skills in Matlab and LaTeX.

Warwick Mathematics Institute, UK - Open Day Speaker

Oct 2014 - Mar 2015

- · Researched and selected relevant information to produce a useful presentation, promoting my department and sharing my experiences.
- · Presented regularly to an audience of over 300 visitors and received positive feedback.
- · Reflected on each performance and improved my presentation skills and adjusted content accordingly.

Warwick in Africa, South Africa - Volunteer Teacher

Jul 2014 - Aug 2014

- · Taught in a township school for 6 weeks. Managed a classroom despite language and cultural barriers.
- · Prepared lessons, covered for teachers, coordinated trips and organised after school clubs.
- · Adapted to work effectively in a disorganised and unpredictable environment with limited resources.
- Equipped teachers with new techniques and classroom activities. The class average increased by 30%.

Harrogate and District NHS Foundation Trust, UK - Volunteer Auditor

Aug 2013

- · Audited a patient care pathway which involved understanding detailed information in a short time.
- · Analysed and interpreted data to report to my manager. Recommended ways to improve the implementation of the pathway.

- · Carried out basic accounting and bookkeeping. Covered the front desk, directly interacting with clients.
- · Communicated with clients to obtain necessary information. Gained experience with SAGE and Excel.

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

Athena Swan - Undergraduate Representative

Mar 2014 - Current

- · Organised surveys, contributed to discussions and proposed ideas to address the gender imbalance in mathematics.
- · Recruited other women and minorities in the undergraduate community to join Athena Swan.
- · Obtained funding and support from the department for weekly coffee mornings aimed at women.
- · Publicised, developed and led coffee mornings. Coordinated speakers, workshops, activities, discussions and a joint staff and student event.
- · Campaigned successfully for a new position on the executive of the Warwick Mathematics Society whose role is to continue and develop these events.
- · Increased the ratio of male to female on the executive of Warwick Mathematics Society from 8:1 in 2014 to 3:2 in 2015, as a direct result.

Warwick Mathematics Society - Revision Guides Editor

Feb 2014 - Feb 2015

- · Edited and printed over 20 revision guides which accumulated in over 3000 printed copies for over 800 members. Arranged the venue, advertising and logistics for the distributions of printed copies.
- · Implemented an online request form to deal with demand and supply issues the society had experienced.
- · Expanded the position which resulted in the appointment of a second editor the following year.
- · Contributed to all aspects of the society. In particular, provided ideas for new initiatives.

Warwick Yoga Society - Head of Class

Feb 2014 - Feb 2015

- · Liaised with the yoga instructor on matters concerning administration, replacements and remuneration.
- · Planned, promoted and ran events as part of a team such as yoga brunch and other socials.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Computing: LaTeX (Advanced), MATLAB (Intermediate), Microsoft Excel (Intermediate), Java (Basic), HTML (Basic), CSS (Basic), Javascript (Basic). To build experience in programming I have recently made a website. This is a working progress and represents my first exposure to html/CSS/JavaScript

Interests: Yoga, Cooking, Reading, Rock Climbing, Badminton, Squash, Swimming, Travelling and Mentoring.

I hold a full, clean driving licence.